<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" ?>
<pageSections>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Ultimate Ascent
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p> The 2013 FIRST Robotics Competition game was Ultimate Ascent. Ultimate Ascent is a frisbee game where the goal is to score as many points as possible by shooting frisbees into designated goals at either end of the field. The game is played on a 27' x 54' field with two pyramid structures located ~1/3 of the way from each alliance wall. The pyramid structures are used as an additional goal and to facilitate the endgame.</p>
             <p>Scoring: The goals are laid out in a triangle formation, with higher goal being worth more points than lower goals. There are disc golf goals located on top of the pyramids worth 5 points each. During the 15-second autonomous period, robots</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Pickup
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>The pickup mechanism used on this year's robot used a challoopa design in order to pickup the frisbees and drop them into the hopper.</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Shooting Mechanism
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>The shooter used in this year's robot consists of a horizontally-mounted single flywheel that rapidly propels the frisbees at the goals. The frisbee is fed into the shooter through a hopper, which stores the frisbees. The whole shooting mechanism is mounted such that the whole shooter can be moved into a flat position when needed. This allowed the robot to drive below the pyramids to take a more direct path around the field or to avoid opponents. </p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Drivetrain
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>2013 marks the second year that GRT's drivetrain team pushed to engineer a compact drivetrain system. This year, the team used a single-speed bevel gear drivetrain to move the robot.  This gearbox worked very well and allowed the robot to move quickly and efficiently around the field. The bevel gear system allowed the gearbox to be very compact and were placed right next to the wheels. This gives more space for the pickup and shooter mechanisms on the robot.</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            The Team
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>GRT had a great season this year GRT was able to get into the playoffs at all of the regional competitions we attended. We won the Utah Regional and were able to advance to the U.S. Championship in St. Louis (Galileo Division). In addition, the team was awarded the Excellence in Engineering Award at Utah.
            In general our robot was well built and shot frisbees quite consistently, allowing us to score goals efficiently.</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
</pageSections>
