<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" ?>
<pageSections>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Animation
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span class="title bold">About</span>
                    The animation group produces 3D animations to compete for the annual FIRST Robotics Safety Animation Award and Digital Animation Award. The group works with software such as Autodesk Maya, Adobe Photoshop, and Adobe Premiere to create original and expressive animations while highlighting some of the medium's most exciting possibilities. Members work together to write stories, model objects, animate characters, and develop scenes.
                </p>

                <p><span class="title bold">Projects</span>
                    Due to the COVID-19 outbreak, in 2021 the animation team continued to participate in the Safety Animation Project and FIRST Competition Project. For this competition, we follow a certain theme announced by FIRST and create a storyline and scenes and produce an animation including a soundtrack. The Safety Animation Project is focused on the theme of safety.
                
                </p>

                <div width="100%" text-align="center">
                    <iframe width="100%" height="500px" display="block" margin-left="auto" margin-right="auto" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLPDNSe7IWHTy2KebpvTLlg_2SjrqGteBk" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen></iframe>
                </div>

                <div class="image-container">
                    <img src="imageAssets/subgroups/Animation1.jpg" alt="cream-filled cookies and personal projects">
                </div>


                <p><span class="title bold">Additional Animation Projects</span>
                For the 2020-21 FRC Game Design Challenge, the animation team worked with the Game Design project group to create a storyboard and script for an animation for their game submission.<br><br>In the 2018-2019 season, GRT prepared for the build season by producing its own offseason robotics competition. The project was meant to mirror the feeling of build season and gave rookies a taste of the second semester rush. The animation Team provided graphics to flesh-out the rulebook and represent important parts of the game visually.

                </p>

               <div class="image-container">
                <img src="imageAssets/subgroups/Animation2.jpg" alt="Cabinet Clash 2017">

                </div>

                <p><span class="title bold">Training</span>
                Animation team rookies are not required to have any animation knowledge prior to joining. At the beginning of each year, the animation lead organizes 3D modeling sessions in which both rookies and veterans can work together. Veterans teach rookies what they need to know to participate. Rookies also utilize free, online resources such as YouTube tutorials, 3D modeling forums, and open source projects. After training, all members know how to model, texture, and rig. Animation of models, scene composition, lighting, camera angles, and rendering are all taught by the veterans most experienced in those areas.
                </p>

                ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
</pageSections>
