<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" ?>
<pageSections>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Welding
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span class="title bold">About</span>The GRT welding subgroup is responsible for welding the base and other components, depending on the robot design each year. Members are taught TIG welding, and most of our parts are aluminum (although we work with steel and other materials as well). Creativity and patience are key values, as the welders figure out ideal clamping positions, welding angles, and strategies for retaining a perfectly square base. With the hazards that welding presents, members are required to always have a buddy in the welding room, adding to the synergistic environment of the subgroup.<br><br>
                With the bulk of our work in the beginning of build season, members are often free to join and explore other robot tasks; many enjoy machining or building bumpers, which work well into the end of the season.
                </p>

                <p><span class="title bold">Training</span>Welding rookies are not expected to have previous knowledge about welding, and typically sign up for one-on-one training sessions with the welding lead in late fall and early winter. Other curious team members can also learn to weld, although training time is prioritized towards those who are eager and committed to joining the subgroup. Before officially joining the subgroup, recruits must first pass the welding safety test--a relatively simple assessment on the basic skills and safety rules they learned during their training.<br><br>
                With shop projects occurring during and after the training period, rookies may have a chance to put their training to practice on shop projects robots; this is, however, contingent on the robot design, their skill and comfort level. Generally, a welding rookie's first official welded part will be during build season.
                </p>

                <div class="image-container"><img alt="Welding" src="imageAssets/subgroups/welding.jpg"></div>

                <p><span class="title bold">Current</span>Due to the coronavirus pandemic, no new members were able to be trained in welding this year. The tight proximity of the welding room and the hands-on nature of welding made it impossible to teach, and virtual lessons and videos--although incredibly insightful--are no substitute for practice. Unfortunately, all current welding subgroup members will be graduating this year and a tentative plan for training new welders in late summer/early fall is currently in discussion.</p>


               <img src="imageAssets/subgroups/weldingMasks.JPG" alt="Welding masks">

                ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
</pageSections>
