<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" ?>
<pageSections>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Controls
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p><span class="title bold">About</span>The controls group is responsible for two main tasks:  electrical design and wiring, and software coding. Electrical design involves working with mechanism and drive train teams to incorporate sensors that will collect information necessary to run the robot, and uses technical skills such as crimping, soldering and trouble-shooting to complete the wiring on the robot. Software coding involves designing and writing the code that makes all the mechanisms move while collecting data from on-board sensors, allowing the robot to operate in both autonomous mode and from the driver station in tele-operation mode.  Our code is written in Python, which allows for fast coding during build and competition and is easy to teach to inexperienced coders. Our code repositories are available at: https://github.com/grt192.</p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Robot Vision</span>For the 2016 game, one of our main challenges was developing a working robot vision system. We used OpenCV to detect the goals (marked by reflective tape on the field) and fire boulders automatically. We used vision in autonomous mode to consistently score high goal shots and in teleop mode to make control of the shooter easier for the driver, by aiming and firing at the press of a button.</p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Autonomous</span>Each FIRST match is split into two sections: autonomous and teleop. The autonomous period typically lasts fifteen seconds and allows no driver operation. Each year, there are different tasks that can be completed during autonomous for a variety of points. In years like 2016 when there are many different task options, our team has developed many different autonomous modes. The strategically best option is chosen before each match. For autonomous, we either use hard-coded or recorded values to run the sequence that completes the task. In hard-coded autonomous modes, we manually tell the robot exactly what to do for specified distances or amounts of time. This is useful for simple autonomous procedures. For more complicated ones, we sometimes turn to recording. In this case, a driver will perform the sequence with full control of the robot while our code records the values sent to the different mechanisms. We save the sequence to a file and play back whenever we run autonomous. </p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Python</span>Each year, we build our code off the GRTPyFramework, which we have developed as a basis for our robot code. Beyond basic framework and abstractions, GRTPyFramework provides a method by which more sophisticated logic and abstractions can be developed, provided a particular code structure is followed in line with design methodology. The two most important parts of the code are mechanisms and controllers. For mechanisms, we create classes for each of the mechanisms that includes all of the actions necessary. Controllers dictate how and when the different mechanism actions are called based largely on inputs from our sensors.</p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Electrical</span>The most important part of the electrical system is the Roborio, the onboard computer which controls all of the code. Each motor is controlled by a motor controller (Talon SRX), which allows for variable control. We control the pneumatic actuators through a solenoid. Other components are used for power distribution and conversion of different voltages used across the robot.</p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Training</span>The training for the controls group occurs in the fall semester in two sections: whole team training and specialized training. For whole team training, we spend one day teaching the entire team the basics of electronics and controls components, addressing the broad areas of safety, sensors, and electronic setup of the robot. After this session, in-depth training occurs throughout the rest of the semester for those who are interested in joining the group. For wiring, members are taught crimping and soldering. For coding, we teach how to use Python, the basics of object-oriented programing, and how to use github to collaborate with the rest of the group.</p>
            <div class="image-container">
                <img alt="Ball Pickup" src="imageAssets/first/Groups-Controls.jpg"/>
            </div>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Drive Train
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p><span class="title bold">About</span>Drive trains are the systems that make the robot move, and often form the backbone of the chassis. Our drive train group is well-known within the FIRST Robotics community for our student - designed and built - custom gearboxes, their intricate design work and precision manufacturing.
            Because the need for robot movement is universal to any game design we may be given, the drive train group does significant work during the pre-season (before the design prompt is issued in January) to develop practical, efficient and elegant designs. Design considerations range from power, maneuverability, efficiency and weight, to production concerns such as cost and manufacturability.
            All of the design work, from initial simulations to determine basic power and reduction to the final CAD modeling, is done by our students. These designs then go out to student machinists in our shop, who manufacture high precision parts on our mills and lathes. </p>
            <p><span class="title bold">2 Speed Drive Gearbox</span>One of our main development projects over the last few years has been our 2 speed, ball shifting gearbox. This version is a 3 stage reduction, which allows us to use it with 6 inch or larger wheels (a larger wheel would otherwise gear up the transmission).
            Our gearboxes are by far the smallest of their kind, with a footprint extending from the transmissions only 2.7 inches. This comes courtesy of a several innovations. Most notable are the inverted shifters: these are the pneumatics that drive the shifting cluster, turned around and set within the gearbox itself, cutting about 2 inches out of the width. Using this linkage to pull the shifter from afar, the cluster performs better than an off-the-shelf equivalent, holding a gear and shifting down to 25 PSI of pressure. Other innovations include the first reduction of the gearbox, accomplished through a belt drive on the face of the box. This further reduces profile, and allows the motors to be turned backwards, with most of their volume outside of the robot base area. </p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Belt-in-Tube Transmission</span>For several years now, we have been using a transmission that gets the power to the wheels via a series of GT3 belts, laid inside box-beam transmission tubes. These box-beam tubes create as an effective housing, as well as core members of the robot?s structure. In response to the terrain obstacles of FIRST Stronghold, we adapted this arrangement in a bent-tube design, maintaining the characteristics of our traditional design, while lifting the large front and back wheels off the ground to help us tackle the worst of the obstacles.</p>
            <p><span class="title bold">Training</span>Training of new members of the drive train group is crucial to its success, asuccess, and so it begins as soon as general shop training for the team has completed. The foundation for our designers and machinists alike begins on the lathes, on the lathes, where students learn to manufacture complex, high precision parts.  The technique of try-until-you-succeed works very well, and in the process, the students develop a very keen understanding of how the parts will be interacting in the systems they will go on to design.
            During the later stages of build season, the lead drive train designer(s) for the year will begin working with a small group of students on the intricacies of gearbox and transmission design. The final competition robot will usually include at least one system designed by these trainees, something like a winch or flywheel gearbox.
            After competition seasons end, the drive train design training begins in earnest. Here the designers that have just gone through a year of development, building and competition help their successors through the problems that they faced. This training carries on into the summer, where much of the formality of the earlier lessons is lost, and the mentorship slowly morphs into the new teams research and development for the following year.
            The importance of the effectiveness of this process should be clearly evident. On student design teams such as this, where the turnover of head designers is almost 100% from year to year, it is critical that this knowledge gets passed down, so that we can continue to improve, and further our legacy of stunning student design.</p>
            <div class="image-container">
                <img alt="Ball Pickup" src="imageAssets/first/Groups-DT.jpg"/>
            </div>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            CNC
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span class="title bold">History</span>Here on GRT, we are fortunate enough to have a CNC mill in our shop dedicated to team usage. This opens up all kinds of possibilities when we design and manufacture parts for prototypes, the robot, and all kinds of other projects. Our original CNC mill was a used Hurco machine, far older than the team itself. Although it could produce parts with complex contours, the software was difficult to work with and highly limiting, and the control hardware began to sporadically fail. With a generous grant from our sponsor the Palo Alto Partners In Education, we were able to purchase a Milltronics VKM4 mill in 2009. The CNC is much more complex than using a manual mill. Because of this, we require all students who wish to be trained on the CNC to be well versed with our Bridgeport manual mills. During Fall 2010, a few of our rookie team members took an interest in our machine, affectionately named Fluffy. They spent hours learning machine operation and how to use CAM software with one of our mentors. Ever since then, GRT's CNC group has been a consistent, highly skilled group within the team.</p>
                <p><span class="title bold">Current Work</span>Our primary role within the team is manufacturing the most complicated and intensive mill pieces that the team produces: the plates for our custom gearboxes. Our gearboxes are freshly designed or iterated upon every year, meaning the needs for each run of plates differs from year to year, and often week to week during build. The other primary manufacturing goal of the CNC group also lies within the realm of drive train, and that is manufacturing the box beam tubes that house the belts for the drive system. These two main production tasks require an intense knowledge of our chosen CAM software, MasterCAM, as well as of the machining process in general. To prepare students for this work we run a complex training program every fall to prepare the students in the group for meeting the needs of the team.
                When we do not have any drive train machining on our plates, we transition to producing the more complicated mechanism parts for the robot, that often cannot be produced efficiently on one of our manual mills. If we even get ahead of that task, we start machining less complicated parts to speed up the manufacturing process. Parts run on fluffy are often pocketed in order to save weight for competition requirements and also add a little flair.</p>
                <p><span class="title bold">Challenges</span>The biggest challenge we encounter is workholding. We will often need to come up with creative solutions to holding our stock metal, plastic, or whatever else we happen to be machining. The majority of our time spent using the mill is all about figuring out how to mount the stock for typically unique parts. It will not be uncommon for us to have to creating mounting fixtures, such as aluminum or wooden sub-plates that we bolt and clamp the stock to. Sheet metal tends to be difficult to mount effectively due to bending and the necessity of using a mount plate. The challenge of workholding is greatest when machining very large parts, especially when those parts exceed Fluffy's travel range and require multiple CAMs and remounting, as zeroes and orientation must be maintained when repositioning the part.</p>

                ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Welding
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
                <p><span class="title bold">About</span>We are proud to say that most of our robot is manufactured by students, including the welding. Our shop includes a welding room complete with a TIG welder, two MIG welders, Oxy-Acetylene torch, and various other smaller torches. Support from our wonderful sponsors The Linde Group and Madco Welding provide cylinders of gas required for welding and the supplies needed to maintain our tools.  Welds are stronger, more versatile, and lighter than any other way of connecting the frame of a competition robot where every ounce counts.
                The welding group consists of a few dedicated members who spend many hours in the shop welding parts and mechanisms. It operates in much the same way as the rest of the team does in having the senior members of the welding group teach newer members. Our most common medium is aluminum, though we are versed in steel as well as bronze.</p>
                <p><span class="title bold">What is Welding?</span>For those curious as to just what welding actually is, here is a simple answer: It's not magic. Despite the "pretty" (if you look at it directly) (don't do that) glowing wand and the remarkably magical finished product where there used to be two separate pieces, welding is actually a relatively simple concept and practice. The method is different for each type of welding tool; in our shop we use a machine known as a TIG welder, or Tungsten Inert Gas welder.
                In a TIG welder, an arc is created by an alternating current of electricity which is shielded by an inert gas to prevent atmospheric contamination, usually Argon, CO2, or mix of both. The arc is able to heat the metal to its melting point at which the two pieces of metal will fuse together with the help of some filler metal. The filler metal replaces the volume lost due to penetration and the natural contraction of metals such as aluminum after being heated. As a result of the constant addition of small amounts of filler metal, small beads will form on the weld, giving TIG welding a telltale appearance. </p>
                <p><span class="title bold">Why is it a Unique Opportunity?</span>Welding is a defining experience that is not only invaluable experience for any student, but also represents the self-sustainability and financial responsibility of the Gunn Robotics Team. Students that are involved in welding will have gained a skill that proves they are capable, dedicated, and safe. It shows that a student has implicit knowledge of the structure of the robot. Also, it's pretty darn awesome.
                The team is proud to report a grand total of zero accidents or injuries while using our welders. This is a result of our excellent safety policies and training. Having welders allows the team to enjoy a high degree of flexibility. When welding during build, it is essential that all mechanism groups have access to the frame and a quick return on any part they need welded, which is not possible when parts must be sent out for welding. It is also much cheaper, with terrific sponsors such as Madco and the Linde Group donating the argon gas. This means that our welds are done at next to no cost.</p>
                ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>

</pageSections>
