<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" ?>
<pageSections>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            Build Update
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p> <b> March 28, 2021 </b> </p>
            <p> &emsp;We have just wrapped up our 2021 build season! This year, because of COVID-19, the FIRST challenges we participated in were different from usual. We chose to work on the FIRST Innovation Challenge and the Game Design Challenge. The Innovation Challenge required teams to design a solution, create a business model, and present a pitch on a real-world problem. The Game Design Challenge had teams create a game that could be played by FIRST Robotics Competition teams. Our team split team members into groups for the Innovation Challenge and Game Design Challenge, while other team members worked in their specialized subgroups.</p> <p> &emsp;In the game design group, team members analyzed past FIRST games to help brainstorm ideas for a unique game design. After discussing the 4 different game possibilities that were suggested, the game design group decided on one game: FIRST: Operation Restoration. Then, members worked on designing elements of the exciting new game field using Onshape CAD. Other members created a <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1crQj-iCeEyNO0d23MArrQ6oUAQLaYxVJETiL-zSIr2w/edit?usp=sharing">Game Manual</a> which was modelled off of previous FRC game manuals. Finally, a few team members created a <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/17toSpNJlSzaQwvffXiL3Qul_SIEephpF/view?usp=sharing">game video</a> and logo. Here is a picture of the game design team in their final Zoom call!</p> 
            <p> &emsp;The innovation group was making a soccer ball shooter and kicker wheelchair attachment. They started off with three different mechanism ideas: a spring-powered paddle, a one wheel shooter, and a two wheel shooter. The innovation team split up into four different groups to CAD different mechanism ideas. One group worked on mounting the mechanism to the armrest and footrest and created a laser mount. After a design review with our mentors, we merged into two groups and cut down the mechanisms to the one wheel shooter and spring-powered paddle. After the merger, one of the groups worked on securing the spring onto the mechanism. They adamndomed the rack and pioneer system for the string and winch system, redesigned all of the kart and changed dimensions of the assembly. In addition, they worked on having the shock created by the springs to be absorbed. Currently, the innovation group is working on their pitch and presentation.</p><p> &emsp;In the drive-train subgroup, training on how to CAD swerve has just been completed, which is important for the rookies to learn before the vets graduate. They are now beginning to brainstorm designs and gear ratios for a tank drivetrain. DT will most likely try to make a two speed west coast tank drive, since there is a possibility that GRT will use tank drive in a game with terrain that is difficult to navigate with swerve.</p><p> &emsp;In the controls subgroup, they trained the controls rookies. Currently, controls is working on various projects. They are working on a galactic search challenge. The challenge is to detect balls on a field, navigate to them, and pick them up. In addition, controls is working on programming swerve, finding our position on the field from motion sensors and computer vision, and a controls system for the Innovation Challenge</p><p> &emsp;The animation subgroup formed their team over winter break and went through animation training through January. Towards the end of January, they began working on the FIRST Animation and the theme was quarantine/lockdown. To address the theme, the animation team created an animation about a hungry cowboy who, upon going to the grocery store to buy food, encounters the Corona Virus which chases him all the way to &quot;Desert Valley.&quot; At the Desert Valley they have a stand off after which the cowboy runs back home, exhausted and shaken from his adventure. They finalized and submitted the animation on February 25, and are currently planning out their next project.</p><p> &emsp;Now, we are working on a new team-wide project where we are split into groups and designing mechanisms for our FRC game that we designed.</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
      </section>
</pageSections>
