<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" ?>
<pageSections>
    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            End of the year GRT Update 2021
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>&emsp;At the end of our 2020-2021 GRT school season, we say goodbye to our wonderful seniors as well as continue to work on current projects and goals for the next school year.  This year we participated in the virtual FRC 2021 season with submissions for the Animation Award, the Chairman's Award, the Game Design Challenge, and the Innovation Challenge.  We earned an engineering design award for Game Design, where we created our own game including rules, a CAD model of the playing field, and a game animation.</p>
            
            <img src="/imageAssets/updates/grt-2021-picnic.jpg" alt="GRT Picnic 2021">
            <img src="/imageAssets/updates/class-of-2021-graduation.jpg" alt="GRT Class of 2021 Graduation">
            
            <p>&emsp;Since the re-opening of the Gunn HS campus in March, the majority of our rookies came on campus to participate in hands-on shop training including lathe, mill, and hand tools training.  Our 2021-22 shop trainers are working in the shop over the summer to build a teaching curriculum for the fall and continue to practice machining.  This summer we are also participating in the KLA RoboGames (an event for FRC teams sponsored by Awards by KLA) and we have sent submissions for the innovations award, leadership award, community award, and mentor award.</p>
            
            <p>&emsp;Also this summer, our team has two active projects: the trumpet project and the wheelchair project.  For the wheelchair project (which was also submitted for the innovation challenge), our Innovation Team is working to manufacture a mechanism that attaches onto a wheelchair and allows the user to play soccer while still in the wheelchair.  Having finished the design process, they are now transitioning to in-person manufacturing for our device, which is named the Wheelchair Soccer Buddy.  For the trumpet project, we are building a mechanism to allow a child who is physically disabled to pursue his passion in music.  To do so, we are designing a trumpet standhousing servo-powered valve actuator, which will allow him to play in his most comfortable position and have the strength to operate the trumpet.  We plan to continue building and testing our prototypes for both projects over the summer and finish the projects in the fall.</p>
            
            <img src="/imageAssets/updates/trumpet-cad.PNG" alt="Trumpet CAD">
            
            <p>&emsp;Our plans for next year are the build technical skills that we could not teach this year because of Covid limitations, to hold several team-bonding events such as picnics and camping, and to do our best working as a team and having fun building a robot for the 2022 FIRST Robotics season.</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>

    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            End of the Year Shop Training Update
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>&emsp;This year our shop leads worked hard to create training videos for our shop equipment as in-person hands-on training was not a possibility.  During the last two months of the school year, our rookies trained in-person on the lathe, mill, and hand tools, while some learned pneumatics, welding, and CNC for next year.  Overall, we had a very unique and new experience because of the social distancing requirements; however, we were able to make due with the tools at hand and prepare the team for working in the shop.</p>
            
            <table style="width:100%">
                <tr>
                <td style="text-align:center"><img src="/imageAssets/updates/shop-working1.png"></td>
                <td style="text-align:center"><img src="/imageAssets/updates/shop-working2.png"></td>
                <td style="text-align:center"><img src="/imageAssets/updates/shop-working3.png"></td>
                </tr>
            </table>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>

    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            End of the Year Controls Update
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p>&emsp;This year the controls group taught coding and electronics for Arduino kits to half of the team.  They also wrote code for a galactic search challenge, which is to detect balls on a field, navigate to them, and collect them.  Currently, they are exporting their code onto a new code organization system and working towards using motion sensors and computer vision to identify their robot's position on a field.  They also helped design a control system for the Innovation Challenge Project for the Innovations Team.</p>
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>

    <section>
        <SSTitle>
            End of the Year Drive-train Update
        </SSTitle>
        <SSBody>
            <![CDATA[
            <p> &emsp;This year the drive-train group learned how to CAD a swerve module using OnShape and  to design a west coast tank drive for our next build season. During the swerve CADing process, our team received beneficial practice on OnShape which will come in handy for when we can build a robot for the FIRST season next year. One major accomplishment for our group was being able to successfully design the fork for their swerve module as it is one of the more complicated components of the set. Next year, they plan on learning how to machine their swerve part in the shop since they were not able to get much machining practice this year.</p>
            <img src="/imageAssets/updates/drivetrain-cad.png" alt="Drivetrain CAD">
            ]]>
        </SSBody>
    </section>
</pageSections>